真厉害
Impressive.
没多少新人能打败
Not many recruits could take down
一个体型是自己两倍的守卫
a guard nearly twice their size.
"组织"
2004年
他受过良好的训练
He had the superior training and conditioning.
而你只有本能
All you had were your instincts.
还有牙齿
And your teeth.
一般情况下  这种行为会导致
Normally, such actions would be cause
你立马被除掉
for immediate cancellation.
但你才来几天
But you've only been here a few days,
而"组织"就是给人第二次机会的
and division is all about second chances.
-我想出去  -当然了
- I want out. - But of course.
但得先等你准备好
When you're ready.
等你学到
When you learn that
武力不如阴谋诡计来得有效时
brute force will never be as effective as deception.
你可以集强大和美丽于一身
You can either be powerful and beautiful,
或者你也可以成为野兽
or you can be a wild animal.
但你必须选择
But you have to choose.
我没法为你决定
I can't decide for you.
所以问题是  你想成为哪一种
So the question is, who will you be?
趴下  趴下  趴下
Get down! Get down now! Get down!
-你好啊  菲利普  -等等  等等
- Hello, Philip. - Hey, wait, wait, wait!
我们可以谈谈的
We can discuss this.
别再跟我提交易  别再骗我了
No more deals, no more illusions!
瑞安为了真相牺牲了自己
Ryan sacrificed himself for the truth.
现在该你了
Now it's your turn.
还有别人
There were others.
不止是我  还有别人
It wasn't just me, there were others.
我知道
I know that.
要不我来找你干什么
Why do you think I'm here?
他们的名字
Their names.
这是  这是联系文件
This is the-- this is the contact file.
有他们所有人  整个"集团"
It's all of them, the entire group.
你不能让他们知道是我干的
You can't let it get back to me.
他们会报复我的  不管你把我藏在哪里
They'll retaliate, no matter where you hide me.
相信我  没人会找到你的
Trust me. No one will ever find you.
-干掉一个  -还有七个
- One down. - Seven to go.
联邦当局还未对
Federal authorities have yet
爆炸原因发表意见
to comment on what caused the explosion,
但是警察已经确认这是运送
but marshals have confirmed that this was the convoy
MDK的前任首席财务官
transporting Philip Jones,
菲利普·琼斯的车辆
the former CFO of MDK...
-她到底在做什么  -你们都不敲门的吗
- What the hell is she doing? - Don't you people knock?
正是她告诉你需要做的事
Exactly what she told you needs to be done.
她要除掉"集团"
She's taking out the group.
我告诉过她要一步一步来
And I told her there's a process--
要侦查  搜集证据  抓捕他们
Investigate, collect evidence, ferret them out.
我们不能就这样杀掉他们
We can't just go around killing these people,
就算他们有罪
even if they're dirty.
为什么不行  我觉得这样挺好
Why not? Sounds like a plan to me.
难以置信吧  但其实是有
Hard to believe, but there are ways
不涉及非法行动
of getting things done
就解决问题的方法的
that don't involve illegal activities.
她试过那种方法了
Yeah, well, she tried it that way,
可瑞安却死了
and now Ryan's dead.
你是说你同意她这样做吗
You're saying you agree with this?
不是
No.
我的意思是  她才刚刚开始
What I'm saying is... she's just getting started.
马克·豪沃思  全球顶尖媒体首席执行官
所以我们授予她
So we've given her
总统自由勋章
the Presidential Medal of Freedom,
她成了国家英雄
and she's a national hero.
现在却在外面刺杀
Now she's out there assassinating
福布斯五百强公司的创始人
charter members of the Fortune 500.
威廉·威尔斯  世界货币基金组织主席
好好按摩我的脖子  好吗
Be sure and get my neck, would you?
当然
Of course.
我们政府禁止暗杀行为
Our government forbids the assassination--
别逗了
Don't make me laugh.
我们政府把她训练成了一个杀手
Our government trained her to be an assassin.
大卫·科沃恩  全球金融委员会会长
她从不失手
And she never misses her target.
塔楼俱乐部
仅限会员
所以呢
So what?
尼基在除掉那些
Nikki's wiping out the elites
杀了瑞安  想挑起第三次世界大战的精英
that killed Ryan and tried to start World War III?
不  我们可不想那样
Oh, no. We don't want that.
假设瑞安·弗莱彻的情报是正确的
Let's say Ryan Fletcher's intel is correct,
这个"集团"在世界各地的关键权位
and this group has planted 54 doubles
安插了54个替身
in key positions of power around the world.
尼基塔杀了
What happens after,
傀儡主人之后  会怎么样呢
when Nikita kills the puppet masters?
潜伏特工会自由行动
There would be sleeper agents operating off book.
军官  主管  政客
Military officers, executives, politicians--
所以你得让我们从基地出去
This is why you need to get us off the base.
只有我们才能让她回归正轨
We're the only ones who can reign her in.
-我觉得那样不...  -你找不到她的
- I don't think that's-- - You are not gonna find her.
桑娅已经通过影网搜查她了
Sonya's already looking for her through shadownet,
但是我们在办公室里能做的很有限
but there's only so much we can do from a desk.
我们得出去  这样才能找到她
We need to be on the ground. That's how we'll find her.
是啊  但我们为什么要找到她
Yeah, but why should we?
尼基塔想将万分之一的可能性
Look, Nikita wants to reduce
变成绝不可能
the 1% of the 1% to 0...
还不如拉把椅子把爆米花递过来呢
I say pull up a chair and pass the popcorn.
你真想让无辜的人枉死吗
You really want innocent people to die?
因为现在的情况就是这样
Because that is what is going to happen.
拜托  迈克尔  她不会允许这种事发生的
Come on, Mikey, she wouldn't let that happen.
你真以为自己很了解她  是吧
You really think you know her now, huh?
最开始的时候你不在
But you weren't there in the very beginning.
她刚来时的样子你没见到
You didn't see her when she first came in.
这是她一周内第四次反抗了
This is her fourth incident in her first week,
戴蒙少了半只耳朵
And now Damon's missing half his ear.
大家都知道戴蒙喜欢调戏姑娘
Everyone knows Damon likes to knock the girls around.
总要有人给他点颜色看看了
It was inevitable one of them decided to knock back.
攻击守卫是一回事
Well, it's one thing to go after a guard.
攻击一个想帮助她的人就是另一回事了
It's another to attack someone who's trying to help her.
她跟其他新人一样  需要受训
She needs training, like any recruit.
不  她不同
No, this is different.
她战斗不为目的
She doesn't fight for a purpose.
更像是有东西要逃出她的身体
She fights as if something's trying to get out of her.
她很...
She's...
特别
Special.
危险
Dangerous.
我会建议珀西赶紧脱手
I'm going to recommend to Percy
不要将她纳入"组织"
that we cut our losses and cancel her.
我们谈话那段时间
You know, the entire time we were talking,
她一直想着怎么杀死我
she was trying to figure out a way to kill me.
她的战术感全凭直觉
Her tactical sense is intuitive.
如果我们能对此加以利用
If we could just harness that talent,
她能成为"组织"有史以来最出色的特工
she could be the greatest agent division's ever known.
如果我们控制不了她
But if we can't control it,
她也能成为毁灭我们所有人的武器
she could be the weapon that destroys us all.
这能证明什么
What does that prove?
她的确摧毁了"组织"  有什么不对
She did destroy division. What's wrong with that?
与"组织"  训练  甚至阿曼达都无关
It's not about division or training or even Amanda.
重点是尼基塔  以及她的心灵深处
It's about Nikita and what is deep inside of her.
是她的阴暗面
It's...a darkness.
阿曼达给了她幸福的希望
Look, Amanda showed her happiness,
让她以为一切终将结束  却又粉碎了这希望
the finish line-- and she stole it all away.
换做是谁都会崩溃的
I mean, it's enough to turn anybody upside down.
十年前  我说她可能会毁灭我们所有人
Ten years ago, when I said she could end up
我当时指的是"组织"
destroying us all, I was talking about division.
但如今  我说的是整个世界
But now, I'm talking about the world.
虽然我很爱她  但我不能让这种事发生
As much as I love her, I-I can't let that happen.
阻止她
Stop her.
尽你所能
Do whatever you have to do.
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
尼   基   塔
第 四 季   第 六 集
全剧终
你说她不会来对付我们的
Yeah, well, you said she wouldn't come after us.
-我低估了她的绝望  -太棒了
- I underestimated her desperation. - Great.
你能转达给
Can you just make sure to let
豪沃思  威尔斯和科沃恩吗
Howorth, Wells, and Kwon know that?
等下  你不能
Oh, wait, you can't.
他们已经死了
They're dead.
当下的头等大事是确保
The priority at the moment is to make sure
你和"集团"里其他人的安全
you and the rest of the group remain safe.
尼基塔最擅长逐个击破
Look, Nikita works best when she can divide and conquer.
建议你断了她这个念头
I suggest you deny her that approach
把大家都集合到一处  加强安保
and fortify to a single location.
这地方她一定找不到
Well, this place is totally off the grid.
这里我用了十二个空壳公司作幌子
I ran it through a dozen shell companies,
不会出现在我名下的
so it wouldn't show up under my name.
好极了
Perfect.
我想到对付尼基塔的建议了
I'll come prepared with some recommendations
-就去找你  -不用了
- on how to deal with Nikita. - No.
我会给其他人打电话
I'll call the others,
尼基塔的事我们会讨论
and we'll figure out Nikita.
然后我们再讨论你的问题
And then we'll discuss you.
我
Me?
一直以来  这个"集团"
This group has enjoyed success
都是凭完全隐匿
from a position of absolute secrecy
取得成功的
for generations.
自你加入后
All that started to change
一切就变了
once we brought you on board.
这怎么能怪我
I hardly think I can be blamed.
我明确告诉你
Look, I'll bottom-line it for you--
这个会议只有决策人能参加
This meeting is for decision makers only, all right?
你的过去摆明了你做不了负责人
Your history shows you're not someone who can be in charge.
你就是没这能力
It's just something you're not capable of.
但我会为你说好话的
Hey, but I'll put in a good word for you.
你不知道我有什么能力
You have no idea what I'm capable of.
上一名受害者的
From our last victim.
跟我和萨姆在苏黎世一个
Same as the one that Sam and I found
"商店"特工身上发现的一样
from a shoperative in Zurich.
真棒
Great.
但愿他们的朋友和家庭计划都一致吧
Let's hope they're on the same friends and family plan.
有发现
I got something.
一条信息
A message.
特雷弗·艾德里安好像发起了一次会议
Looks like Trevor Adrian called a meeting.
这些是全球定位坐标
These are GPS coordinates.
在宾厄姆顿附近
Somewhere near Binghamton.
几小时的路程  我们很快就能到
It's a few hours away. We can be there soon.
尼基塔  你确定要这么做吗
Nikita, you sure about this?
这是个绝佳的机会
It's perfect.
他们都聚在一个地方
They'll all be in the same place.
是啊  也就是说得正面迎敌
Right, which means a frontal assault.
而不是在暗处
Not picking them off one by one
将他们逐个击破
from the shadows anymore.
迄今为止  我们的行动都保持低调
So far we've managed to keep your name out of the news.
但这一定会引起轩然大波
But this? This will get loud.
那就来吧
Let it get loud.
你知道不管怎样  我都会帮你
You know that I'm with you, no matter what.
你想上月球
You want to invade the moon,
我就会乘下一艘火箭飞船
and I will find the next rocket ship.
但你要三思
But please,
想想你将跨越的这条界线
think about the line that you're about to cross.
你为正名奋力抗争
You fought so hard to clear your name,
终于受到了人们的认可
and you're finally being recognized
成为真正的英雄
for who you really are-- a hero.
艾丽克丝
Alex,
你总说在我身上学到了很多
you've always said that you've learned so much from me.
我也在你身上学到了很多
And you know what, I've learned a lot from you too.
我学到了
I've learned to...
不再逃避真正的自己
stop running from who I am,
像你一样  接受自我
embrace my identity the way you have.
所以我很清楚我不是什么英雄
That is how I know I'm not a hero.
伯克霍夫  开启影网
Birkhoff, get shadownet up and running.
好的  稍等一分钟
All right, might take a minute.
桑娅将我们接入了国安局的固定卫星
Sonya's getting us an uplink to the NSA's sat servers,
让我们能从空中掌控大局
give us an eye in the sky.
-国安局  -是的
- NSA? - Yeah.
老爸给了我访问权
Dad gave me access.
我们现在是官方人员了  记得吗
We're official now, remember?
-给我一支枪  -什么
- Give me a gun. - What?
给我一支枪  有人来了
Give me a gun. We got company.
给我一支枪
Give me a gun.
放松
Easy.
退下
Stand down.
斯洛克姆上校
Colonel Slocum?
-谁  -军法署的人
- Who? - From the JAG office.
他在基地审问过我们
He interrogated us back at the base.
那是问讯
That was a debrief.
审问可不是这样的
An interrogation would feel a bit different.
-那你是来审问的吗  -监督
- You here to interrogate? - Supervise.
是查普议员的要求
Per Senator Chappell's request.
我们不需要监督
We're fine on our own.
你们没得选
It's not an option.
这不是寻找失踪露营者的实地行动
This isn't a field trip to find a lost camper.
事关国家安全
It's a matter of national security.
军法署军官
You know what, JAG officer,
我们受够你们这些军人了
we've had enough of you soldier types.
带着你那两个手下
Why don't you take your army of two
到别处互相擦枪去吧
and go clean each other's gun somewhere?
你不明白  你们没有被释放
You don't get it. You haven't been released.
而是临时外出
You're out on a temporary pass,
也就是说我们仍要对你负责
which means you are still our responsibility.
你们可能习惯了到处犯法
You may be used to breaking laws
但是以后不会了
all over the planet, but not anymore.
现在这是军事行动了
This is a military operation now.
特雷弗·艾德里安的基地
纽约上洲
那是最后一批人
That's the last of them.
他们全到了
They're all here.
那是什么
What the hell's that?
快走
Come on.
你俩留在这里
You two stay here.
马上离开窗户
Away from the windows now!
你好  我们还没有正式见过面
Hi. We haven't officially met.
我需要接入艾德里安先生家里的
I need access to the security cameras
监控摄像头
at Mr. Adrian's house.
对  纽约上洲的那个
Yes, the one upstate.
他当然知道
Of course he knows I'm doing this.
来电
喂
Hello?
莱昂内尔
Lionel.
阿曼达  你就不能继续死着
Amanda. Why can't you stay dead?
那样我的脸色会不好看
It wasn't a good color on me.
-你想怎么样  -告诉你们一条线索
- What do you want? - To pass along a tip.
尼基塔和艾丽克丝刚刚潜入了
Nikita and Alex have just infiltrated
特雷弗·艾德里安纽约上州的秘密藏身之所
Trevor Adrian's compound in Upstate New York.
和他在一起的
Gathered there with him are
还有三名活着的"集团"成员
the three remaining members of their group.
你告诉我们这些是为了...
And you're telling us this because...
没办法  我们有共同的目标
Well, we both have a common goal.
都想让他们赶紧消失
We both want them out of commission.
-你是说你的老板们  -我炒他们鱿鱼了
- You mean your bosses? - Not anymore.
曾经我也以为他们是很有用的伙伴
For a while, I thought they could be useful partners.
但事实上他们不过又是
But it turns out they're just another group
一群自我感觉良好的土豪
of self-involved, overprivileged men
自以为能玩弄别人的命运于股掌之间
who think they know how best to control other people's destinies.
如果你这样觉得
Well, if that's the way you feel,
何不让尼基塔干脆结果了他们
why don't you let Nikita finish the job?
因为即使杀了他们  她也不会收手
Because she won't stop with them.
等她杀完这些人  我就会成为新目标
Once she's through, I will be her next target.
很显然  我不想被她追着跑
Obviously, I don't want that.
我想你也不愿让她堕落成那样
I don't think you want her going down that path either.
她已经冷酷地杀死三个人了
She's murdered three people in cold blood.
要是她把艾德里安的房子变成了屠宰场
What happens if she turns adrian's place into a slaughterhouse?
你觉得到那个时候
Do you really think there'll
她还会留有一丝良知吗
be anything left of her soul then?
找到了
Got him.
特雷弗·艾德里安
Trevor Adrian,
阿德里恩工业集团继承人
heir to the adrian industrial fortune.
名下有六处房产
Six residences listed,
但没有一处在纽约上州
none of them in upstate New York.
等等  或许还有未登记在案的
Hang on, maybe there's something off the books.
还有几处符合条件的地产
All right, there's a few properties that fit the bill.
找到了
Yeah, I think I got it.
-你有热能图吗  -有  多亏了桑娅
- You got thermal? - Thanks to Sonya, I do.
国安局内网
房子里有六个热度标识
Six heat signatures inside.
分布模式看起来像是有四个人质
Cluster pattern suggests four are hostages.
马上去上州
Get us there, now.
你要明白  我们
You have to understand, all right? We--
我们没法掌控所有的日常行动
We don't know what goes on in our operations at a day-to-day level.
对吧  你要找的是阿曼达
Right? It's really Amanda that you're after.
我很快就会去找她了
I'll get to her soon enough.
但找到她可不是件容易事
Yeah, but she won't be easy to find.
我们把她出来给你  怎么样
What if we give her to you?
我们可以做笔交易
You know, maybe we could work out a deal.
你想和我做交易
Yeah? You want to make me an offer?
让瑞安·弗莱彻活过来
Give me Ryan Fletcher back.
你行吗
Can you do that?
尼基塔  你没必要这样做
Nikita, you don't have to do this.
还有别的方法
There is another way.
我们试过了  结果瑞安死了
We tried the other way, and now Ryan's dead.
瑞安也不想...
Ryan wouldn't have wanted--
瑞安想要找到"集团"
Ryan wanted to get the group.
我这一切都是为了他
He's why I'm doing this.
阿曼达也想让你杀了他们
Amanda wants you to do it too.
不然我们怎么找到你的
How do you think we found you?
她想让你帮她杀人
She wants you to do her dirty work for her.
你杀了这些人  她就赢了
You do this, and she wins.
尼基塔  有人来了
Nikita, we've got company.
你居然派了军队过来
You sent troops?
什么
What?
-我们没有派人  -是我
- No, we didn't send anyone. - I did.
我说的很清楚
I made it very clear.
这是一次军事行动
This is a military operation.
在没有人受伤前  赶快出来
You need to come out before anyone gets hurt.
还有谁在外面
Who else is still out there?
一队武装侦察连  他们已经瞄准就位了
Force recon. And they're on a hair trigger.
再帮我挡住他们一会儿
Just hold them off for me for a little bit longer.
尼基塔  我不是来给你打掩护的
Nikita, I am not here to run interference for you.
我知道
I know.
我也知道你是迫不得已
And I know that they asked you to this.
他们让你来说服我
They put you up to being my personal connection.
没人强迫我  我是自己来的
No one asked me anything. I'm here on my own.
听着  在事情恶化前  赶快收手
And I'm telling you, stop this before it goes too far.
迈克尔  你不明白
Michael, you don't understand.
我要拿到替身名单了
I'm about to get the list of doubles.
之后呢  你要怎么处理它
And then what? What are you gonna do with it?
我也没什么可选的
I don't really have many options,
但我今天就要将这份名单公之于众
but I'm gonna get this out to the world today.
之后他们想怎么处置我  都无所谓
Then it won't matter what they do to me,
全世界都会知道真相
because the whole world will know the truth.
尼基塔  你应该比任何人
Nikita, more than anyone,
都清楚真相究竟有多危险
you know how dangerous the truth can be--
我们就是这样摧垮组织的
This is how we destroy them.
但你不考虑连带伤害吗
But what about the collateral damage?
-我不在乎  -不  你在乎
- I don't care! - Yes, you do.
不要忘记你...
Remember that you do--
你得想想办法
I need you to do something.
一种试验阶段的神经毒药
This is an experimental neurotoxin.
无色无味
Odorless, tasteless.
进入人体内
It's designed to be in a person's system
却无法检验出来
and be undetectable,
最终把你的内脏变成"黑布丁"
until it turns their organs into blood pudding.
这是MDK设计的
Probably recognize it,
估计你们都认出来了吧
since MDK designed it.
给我替身的名单
Give me the list of doubles,
不然就试试这药的威力吧
or you'll get to see how good your scientists really are.
谁想先来
Who wants a shot?
要杀要剐  痛快点
If you're gonna kill us, get on with it.
-老天  卡尔你别再说了  -你没发现吗
- For god's sake, Carl. - Don't you see?
她在耍我们
She's playing with us.
翻译
冰蓝也想变成大长腿
这些只不过是她的小把戏
This is just cheap theatrics.
翻译
鸟妈好爱看大长腿全剧终正在嘤嘤嘤
挥别大长腿的赫鲁晓夫
翻译
葉子难忘大长腿最爱Nerd
希希狸撒花欢庆MIKI终成眷属
翻译
小憨喜欢尼基塔大团圆
钟爱Miki一万年的瑶莞莞
校对
圈圈2013年最后一个周末冷冰冰泪别大长腿
爱大长腿的真爱鱼不解释
校对
Alex铁粉茶炒栗子挥泪告别特工白富美
时间轴
会想念呆萌Birkhoff的Kallen
Jessie纪念救赎了所有人的勇士Ryan
时间轴
Mikita Forever-紫薰
后期
冰冰要融化了也要抱住大长腿不放手
总监
爱所有人的鱼屎
在吧台  最上面的抽屉
Bar, top drawer.
底部有暗格
There's a false bottom.
激活它
Call it up.
欢迎登陆
特雷弗·艾德里安
替身名单
就是这个  全世界所有被替代的政府官员
That's it--every political official, diplomat,
外交官  军官名字都在这里
and military officer in the world we've replaced.
不论如何
Under no circumstances can she be allowed
不能让她把名单带出来
to get that list out of the house.
我不管你用什么方法
I don't care what you have to do.
必要时暴露你的身份  清楚了吗
Break cover if you must. Are we clear?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
把名单发给媒体
Sending it to the news outlets.
-哪些人  -所有人
- Which ones? - All of them.
这份名单会广泛传播
It's gonna go so far and wide,
没人再能掩盖真相
no one's gonna be able to cover it up.
她在搜索无线信号
She's searching for a wireless signal.
她准备开始传输
She's getting ready to transmit.
少校  你的狙击手就位了吗
Major, do your snipers have a shot?
不不不  再等等
No, no, no. Not yet.
伯克霍夫  好了吗
Birkhoff, are you ready?
快了
Almost there.
信号干扰
信号干扰开启
Jamming field active.
传输错误
伯克霍夫
Birkhoff.
和她保持通话
Keep her on that line.
为什么  你要干嘛
Why, what are you gonna do?
B计划
Plan B.
迈克尔
Michael...
-解除信号屏蔽  -我不是迈克尔
- stop the jamming shield. - This isn't Michael.
-萨姆  -听着  我能理解你
- Sam. - Look, I get it, okay?
我知道这些混蛋该付出代价
I know these bastards deserve to pay.
虽然我不愿承认  但这次迈克尔是对的
But as much as I hate to admit it, Michael's right.
这么做行不通
This ain't the way.
跟你有什么关系
What do you care?
这件事对你也没好处
There's no profit in it for you.
好吧  是我活该
Okay. All right. I deserve that.
但现在你得听我说
But now you gotta listen to me.
你还记得当时在伦敦吗
You remember London?
我那时手里掌握着黑匣子
I had a black box in my hand,
准备把所有秘密公之于众
and I was gonna release the secrets to the world.
你及时制止了我
You stopped me before I made
而你现在正要重蹈我的覆辙
the same mistake you're about to make right now.
你当时因为药物而神志不清
You were suffering from regimen psychosis.
我没有  我比任何时候都清醒
I'm not. My head is clearer than it's ever been.
这跟你清不清醒没关系
It's not about where your head's at.
如果欧文还在  他会说你的心受伤了
If Owen was here, he'd say you're hurting
现在是时候
and that now's the time
去信任那些关心你的人
to trust the people that care about you.
他会告诉你这和你的头脑没关系
He'd tell you it's not about your head.
问问你的内心和灵魂
It's about your heart and your soul.
欧文会这么说的
That's what Owen would say.
帮我接艾丽克丝  就她一个
Patch me in to Alex's comm and only Alex's comm.
艾丽克丝  我是迈克尔
Alex, it's Michael.
别让尼基塔知道你能听见我
Don't let Nikita know you can hear me.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你得制止她犯下大错
You need to stop her from making this mistake.
就是这些人害死了瑞安
These are the people that killed Ryan.
-你何必袒护他们  -和他们无关
- Why are you protecting them? - It's not about them.
我指的是尼基塔准备外传的名单
It's about that list she's trying to send out to the world.
你知道这样做的后果吗
Do you know what'll happen if she succeeds?
不  萨姆  我知道自己在干什么
No, Sam. I know what I'm doing.
告诉迈克尔解除信号干扰
Tell Michael to stop the jamming field,
否则我就杀了他们
or I kill them...
一个不剩
All!
她说要大开杀戒了
Hey, she says she's gonna shoot 'em.
尼基塔  你一开枪
Nikita, if you start shooting,
陆战队就会行动
the marines will attack.
那你可得确保
Then it's your job to make sure
我不是白白牺牲  对吗
I don't die in vain, isn't it?
狙击手已就位
Snipers have a shot.
可以行动吗
Do we have a green light?
尼基塔  求你了
Nikita, please.
我一无所有
I have nothing left.
如果你死了  我也不苟活
If you die, I die.
好吧
All right.
好吧  我们按你说的做
All right, we'll do it your way.
谢谢
Thank you.
狙击手放下武器  再说一遍  放下武器
Stand the snipers down. Repeat, stand down.
需要接入安保服务器
Need to access a secure server.
好  伯克霍夫会打开数据通道
Okay. Birkhoff will open a data channel.
把文件传过来
Transfer the file through it.
我们一收到文件
Once we receive the file,
陆战队就会撤离
the marines will back off,
你们就可以安全出来了
and then you can come out peacefully.
数据通道开启
传输中
伯克霍夫  你收到了吗
Birkhoff, did you get it?
文件位置改变
收到文件了吗
Did you get the file?
文件转移
收到了  我把文件存到安全的地方了
I did, and I sent it someplace safe.
你在说些什么  什么安全地方
What are you talking about, someplace safe?
尼基  你还记得"血色丰收"任务吗
Nikki, remember Operation Red Harvest?
如果记得  你就知道我把文件存在哪儿了
If you do, then you'll know where I sent the file.
相同的服务器和密码
Same server, same pass code.
-你到底在干什么  -尼基是对的
- What the hell are you doing? - Nikki's right.
太多秘密  太多谎言
Too many secrets, too many lies.
立刻把文件交出来
Turn that file over now!
-别激动  -把枪放下
- Relax. - Put it down!
除非他交出那份文件
Not until he turns over that file.
我会把你们全都解决掉
I will put all of you down!
放松
Easy.
尼基塔  你在做什么
Nikita, what are you doing?
伯克霍夫给了我第二次机会
Birkhoff's given me a second chance.
我不会再浪费了
I'm not gonna waste it.
别这么做
Don't do this.
艾丽克丝
Alex!
别管我
Get out of my way.
曾训练我的那个你会希望我阻止你的
The person who trained me would want me to stop you.
你曾经救过我  现在我也要救你
You saved me once. Now I'm trying to save you.
我们不能发布那份文件
We can't release that file.
我是斯洛克姆  行动  快行动
This is Slocum. Raid! Raid! Raid!
趴下  立刻趴下
Get down, get down, right now!
她已经被放倒了
She's down!
-我投降  -趴到地上
- I surrender! - Down on the floor!
瀑布岭重刑监狱
弗吉尼亚州
已经在对她进行处理了
She's being processed right now.
我们把那个叫乌迪诺夫的女人也抓来了
And we brought in the Udinov woman as well.
她被关在D区
She's in D-Block.
我还逮捕了那黑客  把他录入了系统
I also arrested and booked that hacker.
不过那份名单还没找到
That list is still out there.
如果我们能找到的话...
If we're to have any hope of recovering it...
阿曼达呢
What about Amanda?
没有迹象表明她在那房子里
No sign of her at the house.
参议员  我请求您批准隔离F区
Senator, I requested your approval to isolate F-Block.
别紧张  已经隔离了
Relax. It's done.
这可不代表我愿意这么做
Doesn't mean I like it.
长官  我需要隔离这整个区域
Sir, I need the entire wing to be isolated.
我们都知道她有多危险
We all know how dangerous she is.
别废话了  我知道你为什么要这样
Oh, cut the crap. I know why you want it,
在美国领土上不该发生这种事
and it's not supposed to happen on American soil.
队伍里的其他人呢
Now what about the rest of the team?
我觉得没必要把他们也拘押
I didn't see the need to bring them into custody.
放心吧  他们都不会再掺和进来了
Rest assured, they're no longer part of the process.
你觉得那里会戒备森严吗
You think there's gonna be a lot of security?
猜都不用猜
Take a wild guess.
-带够家伙了吗  -希望这一切都值得
- Got enough firepower? - I just hope it's all worth it.
尼基塔现在处境危险
Nikita's in a real bad spot right now,
而且几乎是我们害的
and we kinda put her there.
她知道她自己会陷入什么境况
She knew what she was getting into.
我不会把名单给你的
I'm not giving you that list.
这里是世界上最安全的监狱里
This is the most secure wing
最安全的区域
in one of the most secure prisons on the planet.
禁闭监舍装着强化钢制的门
Solitary cells with steel-reinforced doors,
当然还有实时监控
and of course, constant surveillance.
不过监控被切断了
Although that's been shut off.
而且这整个区域已经清空了
And the entire wing's been emptied.
做什么  折磨我吗  祝你好运
For what? Torture? Good luck.
不  不是折磨
No, not torture.
我只是需要确定
I just needed to make sure
没人能听到或者看到
no one would ever hear or see
这里将发生的事
what's gonna happen here.
这里安全了
All clear!
你就一定要来落井下石  是不是
You just had to twist the knife, didn't you?
不  尼基塔  我是来谢谢你的
No, Nikita. I'm here to thank you.
这监狱的这一部分在我控制之下
I control this wing of the prison,
多亏了你  我还掌控着遍布世界各地的
and thanks to you, I also control 54 agents
五十四名探员
all over the world.
各个身居要职  权倾朝野  完全忠于我
Highly placed, powerful, and completely loyal to me.
你会为我这么做的  是吧
当然  我们这可是在谋划大事
如果我能用沙林毒气  伤亡人数会更多
If I use the sarin gas, the casualties will be greater.
真不可思议
Impressive work.
他们的反应似乎都很不错
And they all seem to respond well.
他们都经历了你经历过的调整
Well, they all went through the same adjustment you went through.
现在都清楚谁是老大了
And now they all know who's in charge.
我还有那份
I still have that master list
放在加密过的服务器里的文件
on an encrypted cloud server.
不  你没有
No, you don't.
伯克霍夫不是唯一
Birkhoff isn't the only one
记得"血色丰收"任务的人
who remembers Operation Red Harvest.
找到那份文件不是很难
The list wasn't that hard to find.
你把它清除了
You erased it?
我买下了拥有那个服务器的公司
I bought the company who owns the server,
然后切断了整个服务器群
and then I shut down the entire server farm.
就是这样了  尼基塔
This is it, Nikita.
这就是结局
This is the end.
因为你  我成为了另一个人
I'm a new woman because of you.
我焕然新生了
I'm transformed.
你的脸倒是焕然一新
Your face is transformed.
是瑞安送你的礼物吧
Is that a gift from Ryan?
这跟你所忍受的一切比起来算不上什么
Oh, no, this is nothing compared to what you've endured.
所有那些杀戮
All that killing.
我知道都会撕裂着你的内心
I know how it must have torn you apart,
唤醒你心中的恶魔
resurrecting the monster inside.
我明白这一切因为
I know because I understand
我知道你心中黑暗的一面是怎么形成的
where that darkness was formed.
因为你在无尽的虐待下长大
The abuse you endured growing up.
我明白这一切  因为我也曾跟你一样
I know because I was formed in the same place.
但今天我克服了这一切
But today, I rose above it all.
这并不容易
It wasn't easy.
一直以来  你都是一名天生的领导者
You were always a natural leader.
当然这并不是我促使的
I didn't encourage it, of course.
不是我在"组织"里教你的
Not inside division.
但在你离开我后
But after you left me,
你组织起来的这支队伍
this team you put together--
他们跟随你  指望你
They followed you, they looked to you.
瑞安为你而死
Ryan gave his life for you.
而我必须艰难地爬到最顶层
I had to claw my way to the top,
战胜珀西  击败"上峰"和"集团"
past Percy, past oversight, the group.
很久之前  我曾给你选择的机会
A long time ago, I gave you a choice--
残忍或欺骗
Brutality or deception.
你本应该听我的话
You should have listened to me
听迈克尔和艾丽克丝的
and to Michael, to Alex.
我要把你留在这儿
I'm going to leave you here...
没人找得到你  没人知道你的音讯
where no one will ever see or hear from you again.
但你能聊以自慰的是
But you can take comfort in knowing
你永远不会被忘记
that you will never be forgotten.
我认识医生能移除这道疤痕
I have doctors who can take this scar away.
但我要留下它  作为警醒
But I'm going to leave it as a reminder.
不只提醒我  你今日的所作所为
Not only for what you did today,
更让我牢记你给我留下的每一道伤口
but for every wound you ever inflicted on me.
但阿曼达
But, Amanda...
我还没结束呢
I'm not done.
斯洛克姆
Slocum!
我不是魔鬼
I am not a monster.
我只是想让你这么认为
I just wanted you to think I was.
给她看看  呆子
Show her, nerd.
我谁都没杀
I didn't kill anyone.
我的确听了迈克尔和艾丽克丝的话
And I did listen to Michael and Alex
是的  甚至是你的话
And, yes, even you.
对吗  艾丽克丝
Didn't I, Alex?
暴力的力量远不及欺骗
Brute force will never be as powerful as deception.
我们要好好吓吓那些高层中的人渣
We got to scare the crap out of some top-shelf dirtbags.
他们当时真以为自己要死了
They actually thought they were going to die.
我们最后一个目标
From our last victim.
这个计划是通过对"集团"实施行动
The plan was to work our way through the group
最终找到你
all the way to you.
但你召集了一次会议
But you called a meeting,
使得计划进展得更为顺利
which made it that much easier.
在艾德里安家发生的事是一场重头戏
Adrian's house was the big show,
我们让他成了主角
And we made him the star.
这都是为了拿到那个名单
It was all about getting that list.
那个神经毒药是改良型的河豚毒素
That neurotoxin was a modified form of tetrodotoxin,
会出现类似死亡的症状  但没有副作用
death-like symptoms, but without the lasting side effects.
至于那把枪
But that gun?
那是尼基塔的主意
Well, that was nikita's idea.
子弹是不致命的镇静药
Nonlethal tranq rounds.
样子和声音都像是真家伙
Look and sound like the real thing,
但它们只会让人昏睡
But all they do is put you to bed.
我们拿到名单后  呆子就开工了
After we got the list, nerd went to work.
尼基塔让我进入艾德里安的笔记本
Nikki gave me full access to Adrian's laptop.
我追踪了他接触过的所有"商店"
I tracked down all the shop facilities he'd been talking to.
结果发现  其实只有一家
Turns out, it was just one.
复制中心  组织状态  活跃
宾夕法尼亚州西部  对吗  改建的煤矿
Western Pennsylvania, right? Converted coal mine?
你在花名册上把它叫做"复制中心"
Your roster listed it as "Replication Center."
这玩具厂的名字真不错
Fancy name for toy factory,
你在那里生产你的发条玩偶
where you make your little wind-up dolls.
但你喜欢留着原版  是吧
But you like to keep the originals, don't you?
这点我最清楚不过了
Nobody knows that better than me.
但没有斯洛克姆  计划也不会成功
But none of this could have happened without Slocum.
他是我们的观众  多亏他  你也成了观众
He was our audience, and through him, you.
你们怎么知道他是替身
How did you know he was a double?
瑞安死前告诉我的
Ryan told me on his deathbed.
相信我  就为接近你
And trust me, I wanted to kill Slocum
我想杀了斯洛克姆
and every single member of the group
和"集团"里的每一个人
Just to get to you.
我真想把你的肠子扯出来
I was gonna rip your guts out
抹在墙上
and wipe the walls with them.
但我的朋友  我的家人
But my friends, my family--
他们提醒我  我能做得更好
They reminded me that I'm better than that.
正确的做法是
And that the right thing to do
引你上钩  而不是杀了你
would be to lure you in, not kill you.
无论如何
Under no circumstances can
不能让她把名单带出来
she be allowed to get that list out of that house.
我不管你用什么方法
I don't care what you have to do
为了达到目的
And in order to do that,
我需要让你误以为我迷失了方向
I needed you to feel that I'd lost my way.
我需要成为多年前
I needed to become the destroyer
你初见我时的那个破坏者
that you met all those years ago.
你还记得她吗
Remember her?
我记得
I do.
她是我的一部分
She is a part of me.
她永远都会是
And she always will be,
但她不是我的全部
But she's not everything.
你让我选择成为怎样的人
You asked me to choose, who will I be?
这就是我的选择
This is my choice.
外面有我忠实的随从
There are people out there loyal to me.
他们会找到我
They will find me.
没有人会找到你
No one will ever find you.
欢迎回到基地
Welcome back to the basement...
海伦
Helen.
尼基塔
Nikita!
让海军陆战队将你擒获是一招险棋啊
That was a risky move, letting the marines take you down.
之前我一直以为
Right up till then,
你已经完全失去理智了呢
I thought you had really gone off the rails.
很抱歉没有提前向你告知我们的计划
I'm sorry we couldn't bring you into the loop sooner.
只有瞒过所有人
The only way this was going to work
这个计划才能成功
was if everyone bought into it.
不用道歉
Don't apologize.
你们与我所共事的人不同
Unlike the people I usually work with,
你们能实实在在解决问题
you guys actually get things done.
联合秘密计划在三十八分钟前就开始了
The coordinated sting started 38 minutes ago.
中情局  联调局  国际刑警
CIA, FBI, Interpol all working in concert
携手在世界范围内秘密抓捕替身
to bring in the doubles around the world, quietly.
谢谢你  参议员
Thank you, senator.
不用客气
No.
谢谢你才对
Thank you.
你们的赦免状都已经签发完毕
Your pardons have all been signed.
旧的篇章已成为过去
This chapter of history is over,
新的开始在前方等着你们
and a new one's begun, for all of you.
但有一个人除外
All but one of us.
瑞安·弗莱彻的奉献得到了认可
Ryan Fletcher's service has been recognized.
谨以此纪念为国家奉献生命的中情局特工
历史会铭记他的
He'll be remembered.
瑞安·弗莱彻
你发现了谎言
You saw the lies.
你知道总会有人
You knew there'd always be someone
滥用权力
who would abuse their power.
因此你才指望我们
That's why you looked to us.
他让我们成为真正的英雄
He made us better heroes.
瑞安给我们送来了礼物
Now Ryan is giving us a gift.
那就是自由
Freedom.
演讲结束后  西边入口处
There will be a car outside the west entrance
会有一辆车等你
after the speech.
由两个人守着
Stationed two men there.
有必要吗  一场普通的人权会议而已
Is that really necessary? It's a human rights conference.
不用小题大做
They don't get that rowdy.
我在尽力做好我的工作
Hey, I'm trying to be responsible.
有工作的人不都这样吗
Isn't that what people with jobs do?
你需要这笔钱
Hey, you need the money.
你这个伴也挺不错的
The company's not so bad either.
晚上一起吃饭吧
Dinner later?
你需要有人帮你开红酒吗
Why, you need someone to open the wine?
不是  你应该知道我不喝酒
No, I don't drink, which you should know about me.
难道有别的惊喜
Any other surprises?
有请亚历山德拉·乌迪诺夫
Alexandra Udinov.
如今我们可以
Now we can find our place
到世界上任何我们想去的地方
in the world, wherever that might be.
暗影行者打算从阴暗处走出来了对吧
So shadowwalker is coming out of the shadows.
可以这样讲
That's one way of putting it, yeah.
这是否意味着你将合法化
Does this mean you're going legit?
合法化
Legit?
我不知道
Yeah, I don't know.
我不是一个墨守成规的人
I've never really done lockstep.
有个女孩在伦敦等我
I've got a girl waiting for me in London.
她让我相信公开"暗影网"的代码
She convinced me sharing the code
是一件正确的事
was the right thing to do.
没错  说到"暗影网"
Yes. Shadownet.
你声称"暗影网"能保护普通人
You claim this will protect regular folks
免受政府特工的秘密监控
against government agencies that spy on them?
这可以叫做
So this is what--
"大众的数据自由"吗
Digital freedom for the masses?
我更喜欢
I'd say more like...
"无政府下的源代码开放"
Open-source anarchy.
我喜欢这个名字  记下来
Yeah, I like that. Write that down.
-"无政府的源代码开放"  -没问题
- "Open-source anarchy." - Okay.
"开放"与"源代码"中间加个连字符号
Hyphen in between "Open" and "Source."
这个名字一定会让公众震惊的
You know, this is gonna freak some people out.
没错
Good.
That's good.
自由是一件让人感觉恐怖的事
Freedom's a scary thing, though.
因为我们只需要对自己有个交代就行了
We've got no one to answer to but ourselves.
以前我们得向别人交代
We used to answer to them.
虽然那个孤儿没人要  但世界却需要她
The stepchild nobody wanted but the world needed.
厄瓜多尔  蒙皮齐
挥泪送别大长腿！四年的时光，感谢所有观众小盆友的陪伴！四年里参加过尼基塔字幕制作的小伙伴将近100人，我们一起笑过一起哭过一起卖过萌一起受过虐，大家都怀着一颗热爱大长腿的心聚在一起，一起努力一起坚持。感谢曾经和现在的所有人，感谢他们的付出和热忱。最后愿青春无悔，愿世界和平；）
这是战争  没有战士我们无法胜利
拿着
你觉得我们私自溜走他们会不会生气
You think they'll be mad we eloped?
我们又不是故意的
Well, it's not like we planned it.
我知道怎么渡蜜月了
I have an idea for the honeymoon.
现在我们终于自由了
Now that we're finally free,
我明白我们为什么这么努力抗争了
I get why we fought so hard.
真正的回报并不是自由
The real gift isn't freedom.
而是我们能用自由做的事
It's what we get to do with it.
我不知道你怎么看
I don't know about you,
但我是无法一直闲坐在沙滩上享受
but I could never just sit on a beach anyway.